oh the air in here is not ideal if only i could
go back in time and monitor the air quality and
have it warn me to close the windows
wait there is a way to do that red is time
series to the rescue let's check it out
[Applause] [Music]
redis time series is a component of redis stack
that has a time series data structure to redis
as you'd expect from redis redis time series
can quickly ingest data samples while still
providing low latency reads and of course there's
a suite of commands that allow you to tailor your
data for real-time tracking secondary indexing
and even control over the data structure's size
let's spend some time covering the basics
for today's example we'll be taking sensor
readings of the air quality around my house to
alert us when we need to close the windows
due to smoke or particulates in the air
we'll use a wi-fi enabled raspberry pi compute
unit attached to an air sensor to take a sniff
every second outside my house we'll create two
of these remote sensors to track the quality of
the front and back of the house we then send each
device's readings to redis time series which is
hosted on redis cloud we can then create a service
to monitor the values and send an alert when the
threshold of clean air has been passed time series
commands are prefixed with ts dot followed by the
actual command to create a time series in redis
use the create command followed by the key name
for our two sensors we'll use dash sensor
colon 1 and particulate dash sensor colon 2.
we are now able to make a few decisions about our
object's behavior with some optional sub commands
adding the retention option allows us to set
how long in milliseconds previous events are
kept since the most recent event insertion
let's say we want to keep the most recent
seven days of sensor readings we'll want to set
the retention time to six hundred and four million
eight hundred thousand milliseconds chunk
size specifies the initial amount of memory
reserved for our time series the default is 4096
kilobytes but we can choose any multiple of eight
the size will double as more space
is needed for the data structure
we'll set the initial chunk size to 16192
to give us plenty of space to work with
duplicate policy lets us decide what to do if
a sample with the same timestamp is inserted
should we go with the default and block it should
we replace it with the newer one replace it if
it's larger add the values together the decision
is unique to each use case and for our particular
case we can choose to replace the sample with the
newest reading just in case we want to replace
obvious errors with an average value lastly
we can add label value pairs to the key for
secondary indexing this will help with querying
which we'll cover later on now that we have our
two time series created we can add samples using
the add command we call add then the specific key
then we include a timestamp in milliseconds
that we want to associate with a sample
we can also use an asterisk to let reddit set the
timestamp based on the redis server system clock
we can also use add to instantiate a new time
series object and add an initial value retention
chunk size duplicate policy labels and all other
options are also available at this point as well
as we use our time series and observance
behavior over time we might need to adjust
a few key specific settings that better suit
our needs if we need to update the options
assigned to an existing time series such as the
retention time duplicate policy and the existing
labels we can use the alter command we can do
this by calling alter with the key we want to
update and the options we want to change note
that any changes you make with alter replaces the
previous configuration of your time series a time
series often contains a large quantity of samples
we may want to retrieve a portion of our time
series to view only samples representing a
specific hour day or time frame of our choosing
to get samples for a given time period from a time
series we use the range command this command's
parameters include start and end timestamps
these specify the boundaries in which we
want to retrieve the time-stamped samples
range has some options that help us get insights
into our time series samples we can use filter
by value with the min and max value pair to
only receive the timestamps and samples within
those two values inclusively using the air quality
sensors example i can call range on a time series
with the filter by value option when i specify
a minimum value of 51 and a maximum value of 100
i'll get a result containing samples where air
quality was in that range this is considered to
be moderate air quality if i filter for values
between 101 and 150 i would receive all the time
stamps that have unhealthy air quality values
lastly with the range commands aggregation option
we can aggregate values of our specified time
range to find the sum the maximum the minimum
and the average this is great for taking samples
from your time series without computing aggregate
values from the entire set of data points yourself
it should be noted that there is also a rev range
command that works exactly as a range command
only in reverse this means that the range will
by default travel from the most recent values
to the oldest this is preferable if you want to
traverse recent timestamps more often than
ones near the beginning of the time series
the range commands are great for when we want a
specific zoomed in view of the samples or want to
retrieve a specified sample range as a computed
average as an example if we're sending our time
series to a monitoring service such as grafana
or prometheus the range command would be called
anytime we want to inspect our samples through a
rolling 24-hour period or the last hourly average
one of the more interesting and useful commands
within the redis time series module is create rule
this command adds timestamps and samples from
one time series to a second time series in an
aggregated form this is great for data compaction
and custom value tracking let's say i want to see
a graphical representation of the samples for my
two air quality sensors i can connect redis to
grfada a data visualization platform to see the
air quality over time this is great but quite
costly for graffana to consume a day's worth of
samples from my time series to create this view
we'll create a new time series called particulate
sensor colon 1 colon average colon 10 store
average values in 10 minute time buckets from
our original particulate sensor 1 time series
we call create rule with the
destination key the target key
the aggregation option with the aggregation
type and time bucket in milliseconds
here i am choosing average and 600 000
milliseconds or 10 minutes the new time
series will now take the average of the last 10
minutes of samples and create a single data point
there will be fewer samples in this time
series but this is perfect for data compaction
where we're not interested in the granular values
but more of an overview this is especially great
for visualizations as the view is less crowded
the size of the time series is smaller and
the rendering takes less time there are many
other aggregation types such as sample count
sum of values min max values standard deviations
and variances of sample sets and populations
make sure to check the documentation for the
full rundown of every command and its options
let's expand on the air sensor example a little
imagine we had a large fleet of air sensors
dispersed throughout our town maybe we'd like to
search for sensors that might have certain zip
codes street names districts or location types
such as residential commercial or industrial
the redis time series has a query index command
that could help of such a search this allows us
to query across all the time series keys to find
matching or non-matching labels and values here
are a few of the query filters that you can use
with the labels these are great if you want a
list of all the keys at the same label value but
not necessarily all the values with only one key
we've only just scratched the surface of what
redis time series can do with time-stamped samples
finance and stock market analysis real-time
device monitoring factory production tracking
historical data analysis the possibilities
are limited only by your imagination
if you would like to learn more about the redis
time series module including more commands and
options not included in this video head
over to our documentation at redis.io
you can always sign up for a free redis stack
database in the cloud to start experimenting
with redis time series so the next time you
find that you're inundated with information
and want to keep track of everything let retta's
time series do the heavy lifting for you you'll
watch an amazement just what you'll be able to
accomplish breathe easy i'll see you next time
[Applause] [Music]